LILI CLIFT

San Marcos, TX 78666 | Phone: (512)738-3988 | Email: liliclift@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/lili-clift/ | GitHub: github.com/LiliCecilia23 Portfolio: lilicecilia23.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with extensive customer service experience educated at UT Austin. Strengths in meeting deadlines, creative problem solving, and communication. Positioned to provide unique perspectives on how clients interact with websites and software platforms by leveraging background in customer service and technical support.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, JSX, Git/Github, Web/Rest APIs, Node.js, jQuery, MySQL, Express, Bootstrap, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Object-Oriented Programming, Bulma, VS Code, Heroku, Canva

Projects

inBloom | github.com/ashlinhanson/inBloom | in-bloom.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary:** inBloom makes plant care streamlined and simple; users are able to keep track of their plants in one place and easily access information about their care specifications.
- **Role:** Wrote all third party API code as well as frontend JavaScript to render API data, developed Sequelize Models, debugged app throughout development process
- Technologies Used: React, MySQL, Sequelize, Node.js, Express, Bootstrap, Git, Heroku

Parks_n_Req | github.com/LiliCecilia23/Parks_n_Req | salty-hamlet-73070.herokuapp.com

- **Summary:** Parks_n_Req provides information about Texas NPS parks and campgrounds and allows the user to make a reservation at their selected site.
- **Role:** Responsible for database modeling and Sequelize interaction, assisted with front-end design and JavaScript behavior as well as rendering data from API and database
- **Technologies Used:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, Node.js, ScrollTrigger, Git, Heroku

Twin Creeks | github.com/LiliCecilia23/twinCreeks | twincreeksbuilders.com

- **Summary:** A freelance project that was collaboratively created for a local carpentry company. It is designed for a simple and intuitive customer experience to help Twin Creeks grow their customer base.
- Role: Designed custom logo using Canva, used client's example images to create before and after as well as project based photos to illustrate their services, helped with layout and styling
- Technologies Used: HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap, Canva, Git

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer

Various Organizations: Austin, TX (Remote)

Jan. 2020 - Present

Designed, coded, and deployed code onto a public web hosting platform. Revised code, layout, and styling to meet client's specifications and responded to their feedback throughout the process.

Enumerator Mar. 2020 – Sept. 2020

US Census Bureau; San Marcos, TX

Trained in official census processes for data collection and respondent interviewing procedures. Learned how to be adaptable in virtually any interview situation in order to obtain accurate data.

Customer Experience Associate

Feb. 2019 - Sept. 2019

Blue Apron; Austin, TX

Responded to customer questions over phone, email, and chat channels. Applied critical thinking and problem solving skills to address each concern as efficiently as possible.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Bootcamp Certificate: University of Texas at Austin

Jan. 2020

A 24-week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills.

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature: University of Texas at Austin

May 2018